<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Of Cabbages and Kings]]></title>
  <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-03T18:08:46+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alexander Papaspyrou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Online Piracy Act]]></title>
    <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2012/01/18/stop-online-piracy-act/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-18T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2012/01/18/stop-online-piracy-act</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script type="text/javascript">var a=new Date,b=a.getUTCHours();if(0==a.getUTCMonth()&&2012==a.getUTCFullYear()&&((18==a.getUTCDate()&&13<=b)||(19==a.getUTCDate()&&0>=b)))window.location="http://sopastrike.com/strike";</script>


<p><img class="right" src="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/images/own/sopa.png">
Today, the Internet <a href="http://sopastrike.com">strikes</a> against censorship.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SuperDrive doesn't]]></title>
    <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/22/superdrive-doesnt/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-22T05:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/22/superdrive-doesnt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes, things come back very quickly.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/images/own/super_drive.png" width="300">
In my last post, I essentially <a href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/13/in-the-boot-camp/">told the tale</a> how I came to buying an optical drive for my laptop. Today, I will tell the tale why I got rid of it again.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Overall, the MacBook Air SuperDrive is a <a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/dvd-drives/apple-macbook-air-superdrive/4505-3212_7-32823484.html">very decent optical drive</a>. It reads and writes <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/MC684ZM/A#overview">all kinds of media</a>, is small (about the size of a jewel case) and light (about two apples, <a href="http://xkcd.com/559/">no pun intended</a>), and – as most Apple products – looks and feels gorgeous.</p>

<p>I was quite happy with it, but given that the only purpose of it was installing Windows 7, I thought it might be a bit of a waste letting it rot away in some desk drawer. Since I have an iMac as well (as a home computer and <a href="http://www.elgato.com/elgato/int/mainmenu/products/software/EyeConnect.html">media hub</a>), I came up with an idea how to recycle the SuperDrive in a beneficial fashion.</p>

<p>My plan was the following:</p>

<ol>
<li>Replace the internal optical drive of the iMac with an SSD.</li>
<li>Attach the MacBook Air SuperDrive via USB, when necessary.</li>
</ol>


<p>This seemed to be a good compromise to me: it would speed up working on the desktop computer, the (seldomly used) optical drive could be plugged in on demand, and some poor Mac user with a broken optical drive would probably pay a few quid for the old drive on eBay.</p>

<p>You might have noticed a certain order in the above list. Luckily, my year-long experience in IT combined with some healthy scepticism told me to start with step 2, and not with step 1.
It turns out that this was a very good idea. The MacBook Air SuperDrive fulfils all marketing promises the name lets you assume: it works on the MacBook Air. And the latest Mac mini. And – drumroll – <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/2627903?start=0&amp;tstart=0">nowhere else</a>.</p>

<p>A quick search on Google yields various explanations for this, the reasoning behind <a href="http://forums.macrumors.com/showthread.php?t=420281">greatly varies</a>, and is usually wrong – no special cable required, no quirky power problems. The drive is just a regular ATAPI-compatible and as such, should work fine on every (even not so) modern system.
If you dig deeper, you find that it doesn&#8217;t work because Apple <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/01/24/confirmed-macbook-air-superdrive-does-not-work-with-other-machi/">made it so</a>. In fact, some guy at Infinite Loop, Cupertino (CA) thought it would be a brilliant idea to replace the IDE-to-USB bridge, a <del>$9</del> $8 <a href="http://www.centrix-intl.com/details.asp?productid=3022">piece of hardware</a>, by some kludge that does nothing more but a handshake with the computer to ensure being useless in most cases. A screwdriver and the aforementioned replacement part, along with a <a href="http://tnkgrl.wordpress.com/2008/06/24/macbook-air-superdrive-for-all/">very decent explanation by some smart person</a>, allows you to fix the problem.</p>

<p>I, however, grew too old already for wasting my time with fixing a product I spent a lot of money for and, although subversive tendencies brought me quite close to doing so, finally decided not to follow the procedure.</p>

<p>Rather than that, I made use of a <a href="http://www.gesetze-im-internet.de/englisch_bgb/englisch_bgb.html#p1025">German law regarding so-called &#8220;doorstep transactions&#8221;</a> (which also covers online retail), which essentially says that you are allowed to order stuff, try it out for 14 days, and – if you don&#8217;t like it – send it back without giving a reason. The retailer (in this case amazon.de) is required to fully refund you, including shipping cost for the return.</p>

<p>So now I have Windows installed, for free, although I would have paid for it. But if you, Apple, really don&#8217;t want my money, then fine: I&#8217;ll find something else to spend it for.</p>

<p>And sorry, Amazon, for wasting your money because of this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudy, with no chance for meat]]></title>
    <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/20/cloudy/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T09:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/20/cloudy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/images/own/meat_skewers.png" width="300">
In my day job as a researcher, from time to time I happen to publish a paper at some scientific conference. <del>This</del>Last week, I was at the <a href="http://www.swinflow.org/confs/cgc2011/">2011 IEEE Cloud and Green Computing conference</a> in Sydney, Australia — but Clouds were yet to be seen.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My main reason for going there was to present on a RESTful rendering of the <a href="http://www.ogf.org/documents/GFD.107.pdf">WS-Agreement protocol</a> and document format. The work was mainly done by a student of mine, who developed it as part of his master thesis, and <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/thijsmetsch">Thijs Metsch</a> helped with the linking to <a href="http://occi-wg.org">OCCI</a> and shared some ideas on improving one thing or the other in the original protocol. If you are interested in this work, <del>drop me a message and I&#8217;ll send you a preprint or wait for</del> <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/DASC.2011.116">grab the final publication on IEEExplore</a>.</p>

<p>The rest of the conference, unfortunately, was not worth traveling <a href="http://www.milecalc.com/mileage-calculator/?city1=FRA&amp;city2=SIN&amp;city3=SYD&amp;city4=&amp;city5=">20,596 miles</a> from Germany to Australia, staying a work week away from the office, and – much to the woes of my family – essentially sacrificing two full weekends just before christmas for flying in and out.</p>

<p>While the scientific talks were very mixed quality and mostly an <a href="http://www.andersen.sdu.dk/vaerk/hersholt/TheEmperorsNewClothes_e.html">emperor&#8217;s new clothes</a> thing for old HPC stuff (you might want to take a look at the proceedings), the most disappointing part were the <a href="http://www.swinflow.org/confs/cgc2011/key.htm">keynotes</a> and the panel discussion.</p>

<p>One was by Ivan Stojmenovic, University of Ottawa. Ivan is well known to the Distributed Systems research community as the editor-in-chief for what probably is the most prestigious journal in this area, the <a href="http://www.computer.org/portal/web/tpds">IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</a>. I was very much looking forward to his speech titled &#8220;Green Computing in Mobile Cloud&#8221;, which was announced as a talk on general issues regarding green system design and the challenges in that context. It then turned out to be a discussion on reuse of already available and otherwise unused resources (those of you around for more than a decade might remember cycle scavenging to be en vogue), and the application thereof in a vision Ivan sketched out under the name of “Vehicular Clouds”. As far as I understood, the general idea is to do intelligent traffic management using the car&#8217;s onboard computing capabilities — awkward at best, but hey, we are researchers. What really made me roll my eyes was the business model behind: the incentive for people sharing their car computing power while at the parking lot in the mall was coupons for the shops. Now why I should sacrifice battery power for traffic routing computation when my car won&#8217;t start after returning from shopping is beyond me, whether having coupons or not.</p>

<p>Another one was by David Abramson, Monash University. David gained some fame with the <a href="http://messagelab.monash.edu.au/Nimrod">Nimrod</a> family of tools for HPC and Grid Computing in the late nineties, a framework for doing scientific computing on the then rather hard to use resources. I had listened to David&#8217;s keynotes one time or the other already, and it was what I expected: advertisement for Nimrod, which his team is still driving forward. The only cloudy thing about it was, as <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/ptroeger/status/146067172723134465">Peter Tröger nicely bottom-lined</a>, that now an actuator (essentially an adapter to a resource) implementation for OCCI is available. So I was again disappointed, but at least not surprised.</p>

<p>Then there was Geoffrey Fox, Indiana University. Geoffrey was one of the masterminds behind the <a href="https://portal.futuregrid.org/">FutureGrid</a> project, a by itself extremely useful testbed for next-generation Grid computing technologies, which is now starting to look at Cloud technology as well. Geoffrey&#8217;s talk was on “Sensor Nets and their Analysis on the Cloud”. I would have liked the talk, if it was on the challenges of large-scale distributed systems (which sensor network are; just consider a medium sized skyscraper and it&#8217;s inhouse monitoring), but instead it featured statements like</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Grids introduced important concepts such as services.&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<p>and</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Most sensors are pretty small.&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<p>Insightful, and well worth traveling around the globe.</p>

<p>Finally, there was <a href="http://www.dr-bhavani.org/">Bhavani Thuraisingham</a>, University of Texas at Dallas. Bhavani has a record of work in the area of security and information assurance, but given that this is not my area of research I did not know her. She spoke about “Cloud-centric Assured Information Sharing”, and I was delighted to get updated on a high level about what is going on in the Cloud research arena. Bhavani&#8217;s talk however turned out to be a <em>tour de force</em> through her <a href="http://www.utdallas.edu/~bxt043000/Research/ext-funded-research.html">latest research grants</a>. Being in this business as well, I really appreciate her effort in fundraising and honor her success in doing so, but it is beyond me why this would be worth a keynote. I hope that the other &#8220;90 keynote presentations&#8221; <a href="http://www.utdallas.edu/~bxt043000/Bhavani-Vitae-October28-2010.pdf">she lists in her CV</a> (see pp. 65) were more interesting. Next time,  I might well just read the two-page abstract in the conference program and skip the one hour talk.</p>

<p>From the three other keynotes, only <a href="http://www.ecu.edu.au/schools/management/about/staff/profiles/professors/professor-craig-standing">Craig Standing</a> from Edith Cowan University left a trace in my memories, who talked about “Social Computing, ICT Developments, and Innovation”. The cloudiness of the talk was again limited, but at least he was a decent speaker talking about something I haven&#8217;t heard before at a scientific conference.</p>

<p>What baffled me most about the keynotes is that, obviously, someone must have hand-selected and invited the speakers. It is not like a paper track where the Program Committee might decide to let things get through the reviews you as the conference chair might not like. On the contrary — it is totally in the hands of the organisers. Therefore, the responsibility for selecting keynote speakers is higher than the one for essentially editing the scientific results.</p>

<p>As a protip for the next year&#8217;s organisers: invite people who have something to say about Cloud Computing, and not the folks trying to keep their stuff alive until retirement. And since you are at it, make sure that you invite speakers, not presenters.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the Boot Camp]]></title>
    <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/13/in-the-boot-camp/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-13T04:35:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2011/12/13/in-the-boot-camp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I confess: I am a Mac user.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/images/own/boot_camp.png" width="400"></p>

<p>These days, it seems that the pendulum of Apple product and service love is swinging slightly more towards the negative side, at least in the community I work in. Partly, this has to do with the never-ending discussion on <a href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">freedom and beer</a>, which seems to be affecting mainly scientists for some nebulous reason—but I digress. Since yesterday, I have to admit they might have a point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I wouldn&#8217;t consider myself being an Apple <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-13416598">Fanboi</a>, but have to admit that, over time, I locked myself into the Jobs prison, and so far, it was a pretty productive experience: The long and arcane enchantments for *NIX that I once had to commit to long-term memory in order to do things that, from today&#8217;s perspective, were not all that impressive, slowly dim away, and in the closed, non-free (neither as in freedom nor as in beer) universe I live in since 2005, things tend to just work.
Of course, each paradise shows cracks if you poke things long enough, and it turns out that my <a href="http://kb.iu.edu/data/abeh.html">rite of passage</a> realising this for the fruity universe was <a href="http://www.apple.com/support/bootcamp/">installing Windows</a>.</p>

<p>Normally, the process of doing this is rather simple. Mac OS X provides a tool, called <em>Boot Camp</em>, which takes your Windows installation media, and more or less without any user interaction, repartitions the disk and prepares everything for rebooting into the well known Windows setup process.</p>

<p>Now I own a very nice MacBook Air (<a href="http://www.engadget.com/2010/10/26/macbook-air-review-late-2010/">late 2010 model</a>), which I use as my main computer. The CPU is fast enough for whatever I do (for everything else, I have a bigger machine), it has a very decent SSD, and–most importantly–lacks an optical drive. And here is where my Boot Camp began.</p>

<p>For some reason that&#8217;s better left to imagination, Boot Camp requires to insert a DVD into your computer to be able to run the installation. Technically, there is absolutely no reason for this: Windows <a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msstore/html/pbPage.Help_Win7_usbdvd_dwnTool">provides tools</a> for installing from USB flash drives, the Mac <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unified_Extensible_Firmware_Interface#Operating_systems">uses EFI for ages</a> to manage its boot process, and booting from USB is working perfectly well in this setting. Or I thought so.</p>

<p>It turns out that it is impossible to convince my computer of doing an USB installation of Windows 7. Although I didn&#8217;t try, I am pretty sure that Vista, XP, and 2000 fail accordingly. A search on the net yields <a href="http://howto.cnet.com/8301-11310_39-20020513-285/install-win-7-on-macbook-air-from-a-usb-drive/">several</a> <a href="http://www.tech-recipes.com/rx/9136/macbook-air-install-windows-7-with-boot-camp-without-an-external-dvd-drive/">tutorials</a> how to do this by using additional software (namely, the very decent open source EFI implementation called &#8221;<a href="http://refit.sourceforge.net">rEFIt</a>&#8221;), but none worked for me. I fiddled around a while, looking at the EFI specs, had some interesting discussions with my Mac in what is usually known as single user boot (yes, <a href="http://osxbook.com/book/bonus/ancient/whatismacosx/arch_boot.html">that&#8217;s possible</a>), and eventually gave up.</p>

<p>The canonical solution to the problem, though, is rather simple: a call to Apple support enlightened me in that I should buy a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Apple-Macbook-Air-SuperDrive-MB397G/dp/B000WHZ0NS">highly overpriced MacBook Air SuperDrive</a>, which I finally did. And trust me: the pain from the stab your computer scientist/engineer ego gets eventually fades away, just like the invocation semantics for <code>awk</code> and `sed did.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sam]]></title>
    <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2010/06/25/dear-sam/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-25T20:22:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2010/06/25/dear-sam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/images/own/dear_sam.png">
In my <a href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2010/06/10/a-dismal-thing/">last post</a>, I referred to an email to Sam Johnston &#8220;explaining my position (and politely admitting what I stated above), hoping that this will both bury the personal issues that arose over the last week, and close a rather bland and unfruitful episode in the history of OGF efforts&#8221;.</p>

<p>I feel that I should share this message with you.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>(fixing two typos on the fly):</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear Sam,</p><p>I am not entirely sure how to start this memo (and whether it really makes sense to do so at all), but despite other peoples&#8217; opinions, I think it is time to sort a few things out after the dust of the recent OCCI / Twitter shootout between us two has settled. I don&#8217;t really expect that you understand or honor my point, but still, I feel that I need to make it clear to you again.</p><p>Regardless of whether you are right or not regarding the procedure of OGF, it&#8217;s IPR policies, the way how working groups are supposed to work, I think that the way you tried to (I like crystal clear wording, so please do not take this personal) defame the work done within OGF was totally inappropriate.</p><p>As said before, it&#8217;s totally up to you to have your personal opinion on what&#8217;s going on there, but going to Twitter and, in direct reaction to OCCI asking you to step down from the secretary position, starting to say that OCCI in particular, and OGF in general are weak, irrelevant, fail to pick up current developments, and get done work at all, was (and is) an opinion I am not willing to accept without comment.</p><p>You have to admit that letting people believe you did 60+% of the spec is not only not true, but also a direct personal insult against all the other people in group discussions at the OGF sessions (which you never attended) and on the mailing list (I remember exhaustive flamewars on several technical issues). I really appreciate your effort for OCCI, and I am totally with you if you say that you are a main contributor, but everything else is quite unfair to the rest of the community.</p><p>I am aware that my statements on Twitter were quite harsh, and probably it was similarly  inappropriate to say that you should &#8220;get over it and stop crying&#8221;, I still feel that claiming to be &#8220;effectively the sole contributor to the OCCI spec&#8221; _is_ not true at all (see my &#8220;damn lie&#8221; statement). Plus, calling the work done (along with the people who did it) &#8220;clusterf*ck&#8221; was also not one of the nicer statements you made, and a quite personal insult. It&#8217;s good that cloud is what you like (and promote), but this does not mean that everything else is bullsh*t&#8230;</p><p>Against this background, I would like to point out my main statement&#8212;and this is what I still believe: by continuously threatening everyone in OCCI  whenever something that you wanted to push forward was not done (let aside whether I liked it or not), you put the group (and several other OGF &#8220;officials&#8221; I am noone of, BTW&#8230;) in jeopardy more than one time and made an originally good relationship with a strong trust in each other FUBAR. The fact that the group was &#8220;not submitting to your will&#8221; should have been a reason to silently and by yourself step down from your position, and leaving people alone. In the background (but remarkably, not within the OCCI group), there was a lot of noise stating the fear that you would start bashing OGF and OCCI as soon as your way would not be followed for any given reason, and you proved those voices (against which I usually backed you, BTW) right.</p><p>I was a bit surprised to read your blog entry, which publicly crucifies me not only as &#8220;some guy on Twitter&#8221;, but as an OGF official (which I am not) by, let&#8217;s carefully formulate, rearranging my statements in a way that is beneficial for supporting your point of view. I don&#8217;t expect an apology, but in case we manage to settle our issues, I would be very happy about a clarification.</p><p>That said, I hope we can somehow manage to overcome this unsavory battle, settle our personal issues, and (again) act as gentlemen with each other. And to make this clear as well: I don&#8217;t expect an apology from you, but&#8212;granted that I believe we can get along again&#8212;it would be great if you could clarify your blog post. And since I am at it: maybe I can even convince you to stop blogging / twittering / *ing doubleplusungood about OGF and OCCI.</p><p>Hope to hear from you.</p><p>Regards,<br/>Alexander</p></blockquote>


<p>Any opinions on this are more than welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Dismal Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2010/06/10/a-dismal-thing/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-10T19:54:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://stage.papaspyrou.name/blog/2010/06/10/a-dismal-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while since I started to consider whether I should have a blog or not. While I was never really against it, and always thought it would be cool, I never had the feeling that my first post would be sufficiently substantial, interesting, or important to let the general public know.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://stage.papaspyrou.name/images/own/dismal_slide.png" width="500"></p>

<p>Yesterday, I brought myself to dispel all doubts.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As most people around me will know, there has been a debate in the context of the <a href="http://www.ogf.org">Open Grid Forum</a> on a quite cool and currently very popular proposed standard for Cloud Computing (IaaS in particular), called <a href="http://occi-wg.org">OCCI</a>. I shall spare you with details (which you&#8217;d better lookup at the <a href="http://www.ogf.org/pipermail/occi-wg/">mailinglist</a>), but the whole story boils down to a disagreement between the working group&#8217;s secretary, Sam Johnston, and the rest of the group on the <a href="http://www.ogf.org/merger_docs/OGFIPRPolicy.pdf">IPR policy</a> under which OCCI would be published: while Sam strived for <a href="http://creativecommons.org">Creative Commons</a>-style licensing, the others wanted to stay with the current, OGF-style, licensing.</p>

<p>After <a href="http://www.ogf.org/pipermail/occi-wg/2010-February/001625.html">extensive</a> <a href="http://www.ogf.org/pipermail/occi-wg/2010-March/001691.html">discussion</a> on the mailinglist, it became clear that there is a fundamental disagreement between Sam as the secretary on one side, and the <a href="http://www.ogf.org/gf/group_info/view.php?group=occi-wg">chairs</a>, the <a href="http://www.ogf.org/About/abt_board.php">Board of Directors</a>, and many other active contributors around OCCI on the other. Moreover, all attempts to settle this via other channels (telcons, private email, you-name-it) deliberately failed. Careful consideration of all assets and drawbacks led to the decision of the group to ask Sam to step down from his position, mainly because his unwilling to compromise on the issue.</p>

<p>The result of this decision was rather unpleasant: Sam decided to <a href="https://twitter.com/samj">tweet out</a> his enragement not only by expressing his disgust with OGF, but also by personally attacking chair and active leader of the group <a href="http://lxnet.org">Thijs Metsch</a>, who I am befriend with. My <a href="https://twitter.com/lxndrp">replies</a> on Twitter were not exactly gentleman-like and overshot the mark (resulting in being blocked by Sam), but expressed my anger about the way things went. A <a href="http://samj.net/2010/06/how-i-tried-to-keep-occi-alive-and.html">followup blog entry</a> and the ongoing Twitter crusade by Sam shed more bitterness, and <a href="http://twitter.com/swardley">different</a> <a href="http://blogs.techworld.com/the-virtual-enterprise/2010/06/stormy-cloud/">people</a> (with diverging opinions) have been commenting on the topic.</p>

<p>On the whole, I have the impression that this whole Sam-not-OCCI-secretary-anymore debate is an ephemeral, and should be treated as such: Meanwhile, OCCI work has been ongoing, and the specification is going to be pushed out within a few days &#8211; another fact that indicates an overheated, overrated debate, the effort that was (and still is) put into (including my own) would have been better yielded in more interesting, more important issues such as the <a href="http://www.ogf.org/pipermail/occi-wg/2010-June/001878.html">HTML5/RDFa rendering</a>.</p>

<p>I sent Sam an email explaining my position (and politely admitting what I just said here), hoping that this will both bury the personal issues that arose over the last week, and close a rather bland and unfruitful episode in the history of OGF efforts.</p>

<p>Although I always thought that the first blog entry one makes should be something cheerful and nice, this rather unpleasant post makes me feel better a bit and allows me to conclude a bumpy week by writing my thoughts down in a publicly accessible way. What remains is a lingering aftertaste and the strange feeling of having done the right thing, but still feeling somewhat uncomfortable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
